主席。
立法會主席。
大家好嘅。
你見到佢見人就肥。
啊！喺度話啊，唔係啊，藍色水質冇害嘅。
咁嗰催淚水咧，哦，我哋可以加上佢。
嗱，即係呢一啲嘅，你撥咗款畀佢咧。
府狀態就係淨係得軍政府噉樣，呢個軍政府咧就係我頭先所講嘅啲警務處嘅人士。
警察部咧就只會係繼續濫用呢一啲嘅器材，或者頭先所講嘅呢一啲嘅車輛。
嗱，你再睇睇咧，其實誒今次修訂案削減佢哋嘅開支咧，啊，你見到嘅啊，特別有幾樣嘢想講嘅。
而我哋睇到咧，其實有咗好多嘅共通點啦，即係誒，包括呢個行政長官辦公室啦，同埋最主要都係警務處。
例如呢一個嘅警隊特別用途車輛，其實咩特別用途咧？佢嘅特別用途咪就係鎮壓市民咯，咪就係水炮車啫嘛，係咪？咁講呢個水炮車過去嘅使用咧，其實係亂嚟嘅。
往往佢哋嘅行為咧係完全冇任何嘅掣肘，去到今天係冇任何一個警察係需要為過去呢幾個月嘅事件嘅暴行係逮捕或者係作出任何真正嘅懲處，而唔係所謂嘅所謂嘅憤青。
由最初時，究竟裏邊有啲咩物質？點解係有藍色？點解喺裏邊有啲催淚水劑？當其時又話啊，藍色水劑咧係冇一個嘅傷害嘅。噉啊，講下講下咧，啊其實又話畀你聽，其實可以加呢個腐蝕水劑，喺度玩捉字謎。
我嘅發言咧，我係將會支持誒一個嘅張超雄議員、胡志偉議員同埋尹兆堅議員嘅修訂案嘅。咁至於原議案咧，我哋係必定係反對嘅。咁其實反對嘅理由咧，喺早前唔同嘅同事啊，或者喺終止辯論嘅時候咧，其實都係有提到過。
嗱，警務處咧，佢嗰個嘅即係輕竹難書，我先頭所講就係話喺過去呢段日子裏邊，大家都睇到呢一個嘅警務處如何地作惡，亦都見到我哋即係成個特區政府好似係一個，我哋有陣時講啲地方咧叫做無警狀況啊，香港咧就係無政。
作用係未必係可以發揮得到。
行政長官辦公室就將佢變為零啦嚇。
嗱，而另一個項咧，亦都係有講嘅削減係乜嘢咧？就係呢個特首辦。
啊！警察咧用呢一架噉樣嘅水炮車經過咧，就向我哋噴射，作出攻擊。
兩個月咁咧，就可以等新財政年度咧，就唔會有一個嘅空隙啊！政府唔會停擺。
可能只不過係得到一部分啊嘅選民嘅支持，未必代表佢嘅聲音係表達嘅大多數。
啊！得意之處咧就係我身邊嘅啊一位毛漢先生，一個嘅誒印度誒協會嘅前主席咧。
而頭先所講嘅，無論係警報問題，無論係點樣使用一啲嘅特別用途車輛等等，嗱，我哋都係表示強烈嘅反對。
咁點解對佢哋又完全唔需要道歉嘅咧？對佢哋係完全冇需要係表示任何嘅歉意，做錯嘢唔緊要嘅，主席。
噉你話啦，噉我哋如何能夠支持佢咧？啊，甚至乎我自己都係其中一個受害者。啊，當然喺清真寺門口根本上係得嗰幾個人喺度，十個八個人喺度啊，亦都唔係咩高舉標語啊、嗌口號啊，全部都冇啲噉嘅事。
但係我哋見到喺過去嗱，我哋其實都貫徹貫徹中。咁舊年我哋都係反對你嘅財政預算嘅。既然我哋舊年反對你嘅財政預算，有乜理由係我哋係同意你信言？而家舊年我哋反對嘅財政預算，係到再營運多一兩個月咧？
事後咧，竟然警務處打電話畀佢喎，同佢道歉喎。林鄭又打電話畀佢喎，同佢道歉喎。但係我哋呢啲咧，唔好話我啊，你話我係一個政治人物啦，我身邊有其他嘅普通市民嘅喎啊，亦都有誒融樂會啊嘅總幹事，噉佢哋絕對揾到個特區政府。
好多人都做錯嘢㗎啊！但係做錯嘢唔認，嗰個慘啊嘛。又或者做錯嘢係完全冇一個制約呢樣嘢，慘啊嘛。呢一個就係見到過去特區政府做嘅嘢就係冇制約噉，所以咧喺立法會作為立法會議員咧，我哋一個立法會議員咧，其實真係個作。
但係整個立法會就可以啦，所以點解喺基本法裏邊或者香港嘅法例裏邊係容許或者係授權啊？立法會係以一個整個立法會去到支持或者否決一啲嘅議案或者一啲嘅撥款咧，當然就係有頭先嘅種種原因啦。因為任何嘅選舉佢可
呢一啲係負責任嘅政府嚟嘅咩？
我再研究下點樣處理你嘅執笠啦～
唔係淨係黃絲爭你，而家黃絲、藍絲九成人都爭你喎。
我都唔知呢個概念點嚟嘅，咪睇得粵語長片多啫。今時今日仲嚇，或者係直頭唔睇電視嘅。
你就捉住一樣又學人哋，又學得唔足呢個特首辦啲人真係。
甚至乎佢哋覺得一直以嚟都係牢牢在手嘅一啲傳統界別嘅人，例如呢一班嘅飲食業界。
噉你講社交距離就唔能夠話啊，因為飲酒所以減少社交距離咩道理嚟㗎？咁啲跳舞班咧啊，你唔去禁曬佢跳舞。
早幾日我都唔知係發生咩事啊！出嚟講又話啊，係啊，飲酒唔好啊，飲酒咧就飲多兩杯就話唔知點樣係會有親密嘅接觸。
音樂班咧嚇，有啲音樂噉，你你一個樂隊咁去側邊噉。而家蘭桂坊種嗰啲都係樂隊嚟嘅喎嚇，咁噉你唔準禁曬佢？
你走去學英國啊？人哋英國都啊撳酒包喎，人哋係有補償啊嘛，人哋係有諗，唔係就係你撳啊嘛，個後果咧。
你澳門都會禁賭場啊，咁香港你唔禁麻雀館啊，機鋪咧啊，種種根本上係好多我哋講緊嘅係嗰個嘅社交距離啊嘛。
咁可想然之啊！呢一個政府可以即係節儉到點，或者係黑人爭到點，係去到而家噉樣嘅民望同埋社會上邊唔同界別嘅人都係噉樣嘅聲音咧？
連帶出嚟嘅問題咧，冇諗嘅喎，唔使諗嘅喎，呢一個噉嘅特首辦完全唔使諗嘅喎。啊，總之你唔賣酒得㗎啦，我唔想知。啊，你冇飯開唔關我事。啊，你執粒唔關我事。
噉係咪啊？喂，根本上都唔係嗰樣嘢。你即係撳一樣酒，呢一個酒只不過係其中一樣嘅嘢啫。啲人飲茶坐得仲密添啦，分分鐘係咪？打麻雀啊，你唔好去撳麻雀麻雀館嚇。
所以我哋先至係用一個整體嘅議會，就希望將頭先所講嘅唔同嘅政治光譜，或者係唔同嘅職業啊、性別啦、年齡啦等等嚇，作為一個比較全面嘅一個嘅表達。咁所以先至會有呢一種嘅授權，令到我哋可以喺今天。
嚟到辯論呢一個嘅議案，而呢個議案頭先都講過㗎啦。我哋係不可能支持。其實呢一種嘅不可能支持咧，喺過去可能喺政府又覺得啊，點解你唔支持啊？啊，呢一個只不過唔係新嘅財政預算，呢一個只不過舊嘅財政預算就頂埋呢個零。
我哋會見到過去一個特首辦或者特別係講緊特首啊，過去嘅表現都唔使講㗎啦。無論喺成個反送中運動又好，或者係轉變到而家嗰個應對武漢肺炎嘅疫情，有好多所謂嘅藍絲嘅人都走出嚟話：而家唔。
呢啲噉嘅接觸或者係話親密接觸係因為飲咗酒咩？係因為飲醉酒咩？唔係啊，係因為啲人扮飲醉酒啊嘛，係咪先會發生㗎嘛？同埋而家啦，所有嘅親密接觸唔係經過飲酒㗎，而家用Apps㗎，噉你咪禁曬所有嘅Apps啊，所有嘅時鐘酒店咪全部禁曬佢噉。
越落。
再打咩？
撳走呢一單嘢咧，佢今日出嚟講嘅話。
電話講啦，相信梗係啦，佢唔出得嚟接受訪問啦。佢話唔關我事㗎，我冇去開會啊嗰次。
哇！呢啲又醒，即係你成日都認為哇，一個團隊啊，一個問責團隊啊，又講到呢一啲嘅誒人事點樣？
係啊！呢一個嘅議會兩次嘅大會，亦都放棄呢一個嘅行會嘅開會，佢又醒喎，唔知係咪其實知嘅咧？嗱，走呢一單嘢。
跟住另外湯嘉華啊，即係仲好嘢，走出嚟又喺度話：，哎呀，到皮不到肉啊！又喺度講埋曬啲，餵你四個人就唔應該走埋一齊啦，即係應該要立例嚟到做添。
制定任何政策，當你製造嘅時間，你必須係要確保顯生嘅效果後遺症，無論係好嘅後遺症定係壞嘅後遺症，你必須係要清楚嚟到沙盤推演，從而制定一啲嘅政策。
當然啦，佢佢佢所謂嘅翻工其實係唔會接觸到市民嘅。嗱，佢根本上咧就係一個好似一個温室嘅效應噉樣，温室嘅環境。佢由佢屋企就跟住上去架車，跟住咧嚟到特首辦，做完嘢就翻屋企。佢全個過程其實佢唔知咩叫民間集股，就係咁簡單。
去點樣減低嗰個影響啊嘛？又或者唔好畀一個政策而衍生一啲記得利益者，唔好畀佢攞咗着數啊嘛？呢個先係政府應該做嘅嘢，先係應該特首辦做嘅嘢啊嘛，去諗嘅嘢啊嘛，特首喺過去咧，人哋即係好標榜咩好打得，我都唔知。
打把有氣憤，而家真係你諗下過去呢幾個月以嚟，佢真係做咗啲乜嘢？香港人係覺得做得啱嘅咧。我真係唔係好知喺過去呢幾個月佢有乜嘢嘅決定出咗嚟，香港人係會拍手掌嘅，係話佢做得好嘅。我真係一樣我都諗唔到。
你見佢而家個民望低到噉，唔係冇佢嘅原因。你都見到呢一個特首辦，其實我都唔知佢係點樣嚟到運作嘅。甚至乎咧，呢一個嘅特首咧，佢好嘢在，即係成日都龍女雞作反嘅。佢成日咧都有啲行會成員咧就走出嚟同佢唱反調嘅啊，甚至乎啦佢。
個好姊妹啊，阿姐姐啊，葉劉淑儀議員啦，今日唔喺度啦嚇，亦都係因為上個星期啊去過呢一個珠海啊。當然我唔知去珠海做乜嘢啦，咁急切咁逼切，就有啲人話就想去尋龍噉樣。噉我唔知係咪真係揾盛龍嗰位啦。咁但係無論點都好啦，即係佢竟然係願意放棄。
嗱，你話係咪死啦？你身邊，你以為呢啲係你嘅盟友啊？轉個頭，個個插你一刀。咁插你一刀嘅有原因㗎嘛？啊，因為你好插啊嘛，係咪先？即係你擰轉背咁又一刀啦，擰轉背又一刀啦。其實全方位佢係可以，無論佢做乜都錯乜嘅，有幾難嘅啊？即係做。
做而家嘅評論啊，或者報紙啊，其實好易做嘅。只要係講林鄭月娥咧，你幾乎係講唔出任何嘅優點，任何一樣嘢都係缺點嚟嘅。你話幾咁易即係收呢個稿費咧？咁多位係咪？甚至乎我而家你要我講講講，我冇㗎。我打開一份文件嘅咋，我唔係真係望住讀㗎。有幾難？一講十五分鐘啦，林鄭。
接受嘅喎，香港人冇問題嘅喎，集以為常嘅喎。你以為當日嘅梁振英可以係啊？邊有人可以仲衰得過梁振英嘅？又真係有嘅喎，佢真係青出於藍㗎呢一位女士，我真係好佩服佢，即係再行到呢一步咧，佢仲可以咁硬住頭皮。我唔知佢每一日翻工啦，或者係誒誒。
點解咧？
你諗一諗。
澳門基本法都冇講過有雙普選嘅。
一個噉嘅女人啊！
係好團結，亦都可以同情心。
下下都問人哋幾拍，下下都係人哋做先，你去抄人。
但係當佢去到一個領導者嘅地位咧，呢一啲嘅缺點咧，就一一呈現喺咁多香港市民嘅眼前。
啊！原來係打柴個蛋啊！你見到即係林鄭，仲要去到而家呢刻，佢啊即係～
嗱，大家都個兩制啫，你可以咁講。喂，如果你話香港嗰個嘅誒民主進程，喂，澳門更加冇添啦，係咪先？
一個咁冇能力嘅特首，我哋點能夠再支持呢一個行政長官辦公室繼續畀錢佢，繼續去支持一個咁廢嘅特首咧？
人哋澳門，人哋個特首做咗幾多個月啫？點解人哋畀佢個掌聲多你咁多嘅咧？你啲嘢～
係啊！你嘅下屬畀啲乜嘢你，噉你就諗住嗰套嘢去做啦。全部都係咧紙上談兵噉啊推出嚟。嗱，呢一個武漢肺炎係完全睇得到佢個能力係去到邊嘅，就唔係我哋以前睇到嘅好打得。
佢接觸嘅官員，佢接觸嘅人啊，個個都以為係啊得啦，我話畀你聽，你啊做啦。係可能以前你唔係一個領導者嘅角色咧，佢只不過執行者角色咧，大家可能覺得係好出色。
咁但係點解你咁都可以差過去嘅咧？嗱，呢一個就係翻翻去我政制問題啦。點解香港冇雙普選呢個先係一個最大嘅問題，令到嗰個特首根本上係冇一個認受性啊嘛，冇一個認受性，特首好頭先咁講，佢都唔理民間疾苦，佢淨係埋頭望住自己本書或者。
眼淚都流埋啦！真係啊，佢真係七情上臉㗎啦，佢已經用盡功力掬到咗幾滴眼淚出嚟。但係香港人都係唔接受㗎，係咪香港人特別冇同情心咧？其實唔係，香港人係好有同情心嘅，特別喺過去呢幾個月嘅政治事件、喺街頭運動、喺呢個反送中浪潮，其實你睇到香港人。
即係噉嘅年紀，我唔係話特別老啊，即係比較年長嘅女人喺呢面前喊，其實你都應該係有叮噹嘅感動啦，都覺得係哎呀，你真係陰公啦，你都係好盡力㗎啦，即係唔應該對你咁差。但係唔係喎，係鬧多兩錢重喎，鬧佢啊，憋啲眼淚出嚟啊，扮喊啊等等喎，咁所以。
走開。
係啊！
Mr. President.
In the past, sorry.
梗係唔可以啦～
And what we have done.
That is put forward in this chamber.
what we are debating today is.
must be deliberated seriously.
Our honourable friends on the opposite side.
一 Resolution proposed by the government, a vote on account.
Under the Public Finance Ordinance, Chapter 2 of the Laws of Hong Kong.
譚文豪議，係我明白泛起公心嘅，誒可唔可以點算法定人數？
但我比較唔同意呢個觀點，因為，Mr. President，任何。
have repeatedly mentioned that this is a kind of routine. This is a kind of normal procedure.
所以我哋係會誒支持頭先所講嘅幾個嘅修正案，亦都係會否決呢一個嘅原議案。報名緊先陳事，梁繼昌議員。
and.
但。
梁繼昌議員。
Okay, Mr President, I'm.
在過去。
now especially, Mr. President, in the past one year, in two thousand and nine.
最高 level of dissatisfaction with the government.
我極度不諒解這態度，因為任何那那係放。
inevitably，I think，our honourable friend on opposite side at this debate。
many in the government would have forgotten. may have may look like to me that they have forgotten that there are.
has been a kind of routine and is normal that I mean, this debate would not take more than a couple of hours.
and unfortunately, since the beginning of this year, with the onslaught of the COVID-19.
深根、orny政治 issue，which the government has not been able to tackle at all.
我們經歷過香港最大的 turbulence，最高 level 或公眾對政府的不信任。
under the agenda of this chamber, I think we need to deliberate, deliberate it properly and carefully.
have to continue with my speech. This debate is on the vote on account, based on a proposal, a motion put forward by the government under the Public Finance Ordinance, Chapter Two.
然而。
now the。
We need to fight the virus together.
secretary has proposed.
this will not distract us from saying that.
this point， we have a very high level of dissatisfaction with the government.
counting back in the colonial era, I would have thought that this is.
一headline figure of 215 billion.
and I could dare say that the level of dissatisfaction and the level of mistrust.
We need to fight it in this city. We need to fight it on a global basis, and this is our common enemy.
spending beginning from the first of April two thousand and two in the resolution.
with the government was the highest, not only after the handover, but I think even counting.
八百六十五萬七百一十三美元的 provisional。
now and of course, this headline figure will be restricted under the resolution under section four.
The political crisis, which was triggered in two thousand and nine, remained unresolved.
And now, of course, they are telling us that we need to tackle, we need to fight the COVID-19 virus. Yes, of course.
啊！
Off.
percentage of restriction.
being restricted by the twenty percent, for example.
say two months, two and half month, which is about twenty percent.
now I do have a problem with the 215 billion because.
of the budget itself, because that will be subject to further debates next week.
That is about one fifth of the total expenditure of the financial year, and of course there are certain
部門，which would have asked for a different figure， they're trying to say they're not。
now，generally，I，think，the，government，is，asking，for，a，provisional，funding，of，20%，of，215，billion.
如果政府係going to ask for basic funding of the operation of the government for
Underline 59，The Government Logistics Department is asking asking for 100% of their budget for 2020-2021.
Now, Mr. President, this is a this debate on provisional funding. We are not debating on the merits.
would be further amended by the exceptions under Schedule One and Schedule Two.
Under section 4A, Roman letter one, two, and section 4B, Roman letter one, two, and the respective.
And of course, the social service department underline 170 is also asking for some items to be funded 100%.
projected。
the budget.
next year's budget。
我會比較 happily。
但不幸地。
The minister is quite happy with.
Granted, this provision of funding.
then I would have be more comfortable.
The already very battered economy.
Based on last year's budget, which is the budget we have already agreed.
我會 not have any issue with it. But however, this 215 billion is based on the
如果某個部門會想一個增強的付款，來 subsidize。
what I would be more comfortable is that if they are based, this they they using a headline figure.
with what he has been doing in the past few years, and with what his predecessors have been doing.
在給一個赤裸裸的政府。 now of course this headline figure can further be adjusted.
By other figures in the more detailed departmental budget, for example, if you would like a an enhanced expenditure for some of the departments to fight the COVID nineteen virus.
政府運 running。
for the next two and half months.
now，which I I think he needs to justify。
proving the whole 215 billion.
我到一定extent會 not disagree with this attitude， but we are not。
The budget, the resources and the mandate to procure.
Why? Of course, I mean this is subject to a more detailed debate.
and inserted a quite a big figure of 215 billion.
and also，I I do hope the minister can in his reply。
We are giving you, the government, just enough resources to keep this.
and there is also line one hundred and six, Mr President, in appendix two, which says miscellaneous, and this miscellaneous.
justify why some of the departments in the schedule one and schedule two would need to deviate.
now many of my colleagues in the opposite camp would say, oh, this is for livelihood, this is for fighting the the COVID-19 virus, and we need to approve this funding.
The medical equipment, the personal protective gears for various colleagues in the civil servants. But I am not going to answer these questions for the minister because he has to do his explanation.
from the 20% limit imposed on the provisional funding. Now, some of the departments, I I I could I could well guess why, because for example, the logistics department, I would have guessed that they would need.
Outlay is one billion dollars and I do need some explanation to that and why he needs this provisional funding of one billion dollars, as and not a a kind of you know percentage cap on this provisional funding.
They are.
resolution is about.
和首席執行官辦公室。
to give you adequate funding.
為咗嘅表現， of the government.
喺2019，過去一whole year。
debate is about and that is what this.
我 must say，extremely disappointed。
for anything that would help.
and these are the controversial issues which I think the public.
至少，一majority sector of the citizens are not.
our economy in the next two and a half months， and that is what this。
And of course, my honourable colleagues on my side has tabled quite a few amendments.
happy with why the government need to spend such money on these departments, including the police.
to provide just adequate funding to fight the COVID-19 virus.
and nothing has been done yet, today, to address the dire political situation we're in. Now, of course.
have。
the virus.
events。
gone and past, and now we are tackling.
now what what is the point of this policy?
但係， of course，我do do有啲 respect for the religion。
you are， we are not a Muslim country。
就 forbid people using the airport for transit.
for the bars and the licensed places to sell alcohol.
但係，什麼是點解要禁售酒精喺呢個城市？
people will still come to the bar to chat. They can order a fruit punch. They can order.
但一啲我唔理解， yesterday係一種禁售酒精。
And I do think that in Muslim countries, they need to ban gambling. They need to ban the sale of alcohol.
Now I must say that the government has been quite slow in implementing, proposing and implementing a lot of these policies.
In recent one or two weeks, now of course we've seen the blunder committed by certain governments in Europe, including Italy, Spain, United States and the United Kingdom.
and of course we've we've seen that the government is trying to close down the borders to foreign visitors, trying to restrict passengers from using the Hong Kong International Airport.
You need.
now if。
This is a.
要規ulate。
坐廳密度。
啊！檸檬茶。
policy blunder， I think。
and have closed social contact.
You need to regulate.
In order to contain the infection.
要 have less social contact. Be realistic. You need.
The number of people sitting at each table.
our situation become worse and worse, you need.
to close down the restaurants and the bars for a couple of weeks.
and I think you need to readdress the situation if you want to distance people if you want
要限制操作 hours operating hours of the restaurants. You need to restrict the operating hours of the restaurants and bars.
Blunder.
sectorial interest.
those clients who brought the alcohol to the place.
Now of course I'm just using this as an illustration.
and this is a highly contagious virus.
inexplicable and and quite stupid, you know, policy moves.
我希望，香港政府，could。
and do not be swayed by any, you know.
I don't see why. I mean, we are debating on how to legislate.
Is it permissible? Are you going to punish the owner of the bar, or are you going to punish?
在， directing your policy. Your policy is for the health.
考慮The wider policy implication more deeply before announcing it in public.
先生，我只用呢個，作為一個，一個政策。
Well, in the past, I think the the Hong Kong SAR government has done a lot of quite, you know.
一 bans on selling of alcohol, and I don't see that would be any easy piece of legislation.
and it would be difficult. and how about people bring alcohol or to the spot and consume on the spot of the the bar or or the licensed place?
Now.
政治嘅 blunder。
and well-being.
Politics here.
個 policy。
我們有個義務。
I'm sorry, this is.
到國際社會， as well.
和香港作為國際城市。
We should be resigning from a seat. This is a place.
立法會，如果我們 not 議論。
所以，why should I be paying you 215 billion dollars for committing these?
for political decision. This is a place for deliberating the different causes.
of the all the citizens of Hong Kong, and not to protect certain sectorial interests.
many of my colleagues in the opposite camps also say this is a kind of livelihood you know debate. We should not pull in too much politics, but
And I think this is a political decision. If we were to vote down on this vote-on-account resolution, thank you, Mr. President.有冇其他議員想發言？
符合公眾利益。
具體安排亦都同過往係完全一致。
政府係有必要提出臨時撥款決議案。
因此，二零二零年撥款條例將唔會喺嗰日期之前實施。
維持日常運作，嚴重影響警務處為市民提供嘅服務。
過去十年只有兩年運用調撥款額嘅權力應付個特別嘅需要。
如果冇，我現在請局長就修訂案發言，之後表決議員提出嘅修訂案。財經事務及僱務局局長。
正如我之前強調，申請臨時撥款係沿用已久，涵蓋所有政策局部門辦公室，包括行政長官辦公室嘅必要程序。
我亦都想強調，財政司司長一向謹慎運用有關嘅權力，並且會喺財委會嘅報告有關權力佢哋嘅使用情況，即係調撥誒款額嘅使用嘅情況。
主席，按照我哋今年財政預算案嘅時間表，二零二零年撥款條例草案嘅最後階段係會喺立法會二零二零年四月二十九號嘅會議上係進行。
為咗確保喺今年四月一號新財政年度開始時，政府唔會因為缺乏資源而需要停止包括教育、社會福利、醫療衞生、保安等與市民息息相關嘅公共服務。
就香港警務處而言，佢個總開支八成到係由員工誒嘅相關開支，係屬於按月支付性質，因此絕對唔會出現由財政司司長一筆過撥款畀警務處嘅情況。
有議員關注臨時撥款額嘅佔款嘅總額嘅整體比例係高達百分之三十四，係較以往為高。正如我之前所講，今年嘅臨時撥款金額二千一百五十九億嘅計算方法同以往係完全一致。
張超雄議員、胡志偉議員同埋尹兆堅議員提交嘅修訂案，建議削減行政長官辦公室同埋香港警務處嘅所有開支，包括個人薪酬。呢啲議案係缺乏理據，而且係極不合理，亦都唔係。
誒，另外亦都有係嗰個。
佔總開支嘅比例大概百分之二，屬於正常水平。
在我請張超雄議員動議去抵項修訂案之前。
誒總目九十，分目二百零，係畀職業安全健康局嘅撥款。
所以，我特區政府我哋係強烈反對有關嘅修訂，並且呼籲議員否決呢啲修訂。多謝主席。
有議員擔心臨時撥款議案獲得通過，會畀政府有過大嘅權力動用撥款。我請議員不必過慮。
總括而言，議員提出嘅四項修訂議案係會嚴重削弱政府有效提供公共服務同埋履行僱主法律責任嘅能力。
有關部門係會等2020年撥款條例草案獲得立法會通過之後，先至會展開有關新嘅項目嘅相關工作。
呢啲新嘅項目係包括添置新裝備同埋開展新計劃等，而呢一項承諾同樣適用於香港警察誒香港警務處。
而警務處嘅非經營開支，即係機械設備同埋工程，包括購置車輛有關嘅開支，都只係約五億元。
執法傷亡賠償噉樣，另外第三類例子咧就係應付緊急災難事故，譬如總目一七零社會福利處分目一七七緊急救濟等。
政府一貫嘅承諾係喺臨臨時撥款期間，有關納入預算裏邊與二零二零年撥款條例草案一同提交立法會審議嘅新嘅項目，係不會有任何開支。
第二方面就係話有啲款項咧，係因為佢嗰個需求變動咗，而嗰個有關嘅款項咧係唔可以延遲支付嘅。個例子就係總目一七零社會福利署分目一七六暴力及。
如果行政長官辦公室喺二零二零年四月一號財政年度開始嘅時候，得唔到所需要嘅資源應付日常開支而冇法運作，將來會嚴重影響行政長官辦公室嘅職能，包括支援行政長官同埋行政會。
二對目前香港嘅抗疫同埋防疫工作嘅統籌，尤其影響極大。另外，就香港警務處而言，其責任係服務社會大眾，維持社會治安同埋維護法紀。議員提出嘅修訂案係會令警務處缺乏足夠嘅資。
如果呢啲修訂議案獲得通過，主要公共服務將會陷入混亂，政府嘅運作亦都會受到嚴重嘅幹擾。呢啲議案係會造成極大嘅負面影響，係唔係符合公眾利益嘅？至於頭先議員有提到關於我哋呢一個經，
常開支嘅分目有一啲嘅誒要求喺個附表一裏邊係多過百分之二十被付款額嘅原因，其實呢啲有幾幾類原因，有一啲係因為啲款項咧係按季度支付，所以變咗四月嗰陣時候傾要支付三個月嘅費用。誒，例如就係好似勞工處。
所以主席，我哋見到呢一啲噉嘅項目係令到我哋個附表一係需要有啲項目係增係多過百分之二十。整體嚟講，我哋主理呢一個誒撥款條例呢個嘅臨時撥款條例嘅誒安排，都係同以往都係一樣噉樣嘅誒安排。
開始票決。
開始表決。
張超雄議員，請你動議你嘅第二項修訂議案。
主席，我同意通過我第二項嘅修訂議案，請記名點票。
點票張超議員應要求記名點票，點會鐘響五分鐘？
代議議題係張超雄議員嘅第二項修訂議案，予以通過。
請核對所在嘅表決，如果冇問題，就停止表決，顯示結果。
議案中嘅總目耶一行政長官辦公室下嘅所有開支。
請核對所作嘅表決，如果冇問題嘅，現在停止表決，顯示結果。功能團體出席三十四位，贊成十位，反對夜三位。
嘅所有開支，因此唔論張超洪議員嘅第二項修訂案是否獲得通過，尹兆堅議員昆不可動議佢嘅第二項修議案。
分區直選嘅出席三十位，贊成係十四位，反對係十六位，議題係未獲得兩部分在席議員分別過半數贊成，我宣佈修訂議案被否決。
我想提醒各位，由於張超雄議員嘅底項修訂議案同胡志偉議員嘅修訂案實質相同，君指在削減局長。
因此，不論張超雄議員嘅第一項修訂議案是否獲得通過，胡志偉議員均不可動議佢嘅修訂案。張超雄議員，請你動議你嘅第一項修訂案。
主席，我同意通過我嘅第一項修訂議案。請記名點票。係張超雄議員嘅第一項修訂案予以通過。張超雄議員要求記名點票，點票鐘響五分鐘。
功能團體出席係三十四位，十位贊成，二十三位反對。分區直選嘅出席嘢八位，贊成十三位，反對十五位。議題係未獲得兩部分在席議員分別要過半數贊成，我宣佈修訂案被否決。
在我請張超雄議員動議佢第二項修訂案之前，我亦都想提醒各位，由於張超雄議員嘅第二項修訂案同尹兆堅議員嘅修訂案實質相同，均指在削減局長議案中總目一二二香港警務處下。
開始表決。
陳淑莊園要求記名點票，點票鐘響五分鐘。
我現在請局長答辯，之後辯論即告結束。財經事務及庫務局局長。
提供各項市民都係關心嘅服務。多謝主席。現在嘅待決議題係局長嘅議案，予以通過。
請核對所在嘅表決，如果冇問題，現在停止表決，顯示結果。出席係六十四位，有三十九位贊成，廿四位反對。議題係獲得在席議員以過半數贊成，我宣佈議案獲得通過。我現在宣佈休會。
主席，現時二零二零年撥款條例草案正交予財務委員會審議，各政策局會喺四月三號至九號舉行嘅財務委員會特別會議上就其政策嘅範疇會作出解釋。誒，議員亦都可以喺四月二十二號同埋。
廿三號第二次財政預算案會議上發表意見，我希望議員支持呢一項決議，畀政府喺二零二零年四月一號新財政年度開始，至到二零二零年撥款條例實施嘅一段期間，係繼續獲得所需要嘅資源，向公。